I'm telling you.
this... this is a bad idea.
I heard there's an 80-foot tall
black walnut tree back here.
We can get 15 grand for one tree.
This is government property.
The road said "closed"
in big red letters.
So. we get in. we get the wood.
we get out.
Is this it?
What are you. a moron?
This tree is coniferous.
Carnivorous? What?
It eats meat?
No. numb nuts.
Needles and cones.
Those don't look like cones to me.
Oh my god!
How could you have hired him?
- Your father was the best candidate.
- Are you sure?
Dad is an excellent liar.
He's an excellent science teacher.
- I called the school where he taught...
- 15 years ago.
And after 15 years.
they still remember him.
They named their lab after your dad.
- I thought you'd be pleased.
- Well. you were incorrect.
- Is there a probation period?
- Yes.
Well. what would please me
is if you terminated him
at the end of that time.
OK. kids. everybody
put on their goggles.
Hello?
Hi. honey.
Okay. ready...
aim. fire.
- The light refracted.
- Yeah. now why is the light visible?
Because the Jell-O molecules
are close together.
- Yeah. but that's not magic. that's...
- Max K. the Science Way.
Science Squad.
meet my daughter. the world
famous anthropologist.
- I taught her everything she knows.
- Actually. I went to college.
I have multiple degrees.
Well. tell the kids a little
something about refraction.
Snell's Law states that
the angle of incidence
is related to the angle
of refraction.
where V equals the wave velocities
through the respective media
and N equals...
Nifty. That's very nifty.
But what was your favorite
example when you were a kid?
Rainbows.
Rainbows. I love rainbows.
Yeah. rainbows.
She used to make me drive her
all the way across town.
to the other side of the rainbow
because she didn't believe that
light came out of the bac
of a raindrop.
Yeah.
So. are there any questions
for our scientist?
- Me. me. me.
- I have to go examine
the frontal bone
of a dead person's skull.
Maybe another time. kids.
Gee. dead person's skull.
Ain't that a kick in the head.
Most likely a wind
deposited them there.
That seems most likely.
The bones didn't come
from the ground.
they didn't come from
the sky. that leaves the wind.
People over there need to clear out.
Those people over there
are looking for the rest of that.
They are right in the middle of
the masked booby migration path.
Masked booby?You're kidding.
The Department of Fish
and Wildlife does not kid.
You just have to give me a minutes.
and you can have your boobies
all to yourself.
What do we got?
This one's a portion of the sacrum.
Definitely human.
There's char marks.
Oh. God.
You know I hate when you
sniff and smell dead things.
Fresh burn.
Days or weeks rather than months.
- I found a hyoid.
- He found a hyoid.
Dead guy's hyoid.
"Guy" as in the sexually nonspecific
urban colloquialism
or in reference to the gender normally
associated with a penis. Mr. Bray?
The penis.
Similar char marks.
Any fires in the last couple weeks?
- No.
- The body of the hyoid is fractured.
- Strangulation.
- This man was murdered.
We'll need to search
this entire area.
According to my scientists.
your boobies are out of luck.
Bones - Season 04 Episode 11
"The Bone that blew"
Hey. good afternoon. Agent Booth.
Wish I could stay and chat.
but I gotta go pick up
my new employment ID.
- Guns of steel.
- You work here now? Max?
You work here now?
I can still make out the accelerant
pour pattern victim
must have been doused postmortem.
I'll have Hodgins run it
through the mass spec.
- Your dad works here now?
- Not my idea.
She wants me to fire him.
- Why?
- This is a crime lab.
My father is a bank robber
and an accused murderer.
Booth's killed more people
than Max has and he works here.
Don't bring that up.
In fact. Dr. Brennan.
you've also killed a person.
And I'll point out.
Max was never convicted.
So. in the eyes of the law.
he's never killed anyone.
- Why are you defending him?
- Why aren't you?
He is your father.
Whose sperm hit whose egg
shouldn't determine who works here.
He's showing kids
arnd the museum. What can it hurt?
Let's get to work. please.
Nothing definitive
on cause of death.
We don't have a lot to work with.
I did find an anomaly.
The victim suffered a
compression fracture sometime between
3 and 6 months prior to his death.
- Why is that an anomaly?
- Compression fractures
are normally associated
with osteoporosis. but
but the sacral vertebrae haven't
even undergone final fusing.
Not even 30 years old.
The fracture must have been
the result of trauma.
A motor vehicle accident.
parachute jumping.
It would have been very painful.
20-something with a bad back.
You gotta give me something here
more to go on.
I would love to give you more.
but that would involve fantasy.
which would be futile.
Excellent. I'll check my e-mail.
It's your lucky day. Booth.
We ran the victim's bone marrow.
We got a hit on
the Armed Forces DNA Registry.
Here's your guy.
- Calvin Warren.
- Force Recon.
Marine Corps Special Ops.
toughest of the tough.
The kind that parachute out of airplanes
and get vertebral compression fractures?
You are a genius. okay?
Did the Marine Corps say
where this guy got to?
They don't know. Warren was honorably
discharged three years ago.
Marines tried to track him down.
see if he wanted to re-up.
checked his credit cards
and bank accounts.
- he's totally off the grid.
- Would his back
be bad enough to medicate?
- Yes.
- Fine. I'll just order a search
of the controlled substance database.
I'll see if I can get an address.
You guys can go back
to your bone play.
Can you believe how light
this thing is?
I'd say six grams.
No way these bones were burned
in an ordinary wood fire.
A wood fire burns
at 800 degrees Fahrenheit.
Human flesh needs 1.400 to ignite.
Why do you know that?
My uncle is a funeral director.
Crematorium will incinerate
a grown man down
- to 5 or 6 pounds.
- These weren't cremated.
The bones would be drier.
the flesh would be completely gone.
That the burn was hotter than
wood fire and cooler than a crematorium.
That's a thousand-degree range.
I may be able
to I.D. the accelerant.
I think we need a broader
picture of the burn conditions.
How are you gonna do that?
We could experiment.
Is that what you're after here?
You'll recall I mostly disapproved
of your experiments with Dr. Addy.
You didn't disapprove the results.
You have me there. Dr. Hodgins.
I can't tell if we're doing
an experiment or not.
Not.
See. I... I don't see
what the problem is.
It's a crime lab.
You're a convicted felon.
Your presence taints the evidence.
But I'm not gonna be
around any evidence.
Basically. I'm just gonna be
firing lasers through stuff.
Oh. look. there's the doc
that told the jury that
I was a sociopath. Hey.
Please. sit down. Doc. How are you?
Likeable sociopath.
So. Cam wants
Hodgins to design an experiment
to figure out how hot a fire was.
Yeah. How hot a fire was
that burned a body.
- What body?
- The bones in the tree-murder victim.
Which is a crime we cannot discuss.
Yeah. but I know exactly
how that experiment should go.
You aren't adequately credentialed
to design an experiment. Dad.
Can I ask what's really going on
between you?
Tempy doesn't want me
working at the Jeffersonian.
Why?
It's a conflict of interest.
We catch criminals.
my dad is a criminal.
- That would be valid...
- Thank you.
... if it were your real reason.
but it's not.
- Yeah. yes. it is.
- No. it's not.
- No. no.
- Yeah.
- No. it's not.
No and this can't be resolved
between you until you confront
the real reason behind your feeling.
What do you say it is?
Well. at the time
you abandoned your daughter
15 years ago. you were a well-regarded
science teacher. Now...
here you are basically
in the same situation.
And subconsciously.
she doesn't want to risk
feeling that sense of abandonment
and bereavement again.
That is such a load of crap.
You are far too rational for that.
Exactly.
FBI got a hit off the controlled
substances database.
I just got off the phone with Booth.
Cal Warren had a prescription
for Oxycodone
written by a Dr. Antonia Ezralow.
office in Chevy Chase.
Could she provide an address?
Dr. Ezralow has never
heard of Calvin Warren.
Plus. she's a dermatologist.
Very rarely writes prescriptions
for pain medication.
So he probably stole
her prescription pad.
Here's his MySpace page.
and I have to say
he doesn't look much
like a drug dealer.
What a waste.
Tall. dark. handsome and dead.
Too bad he's blocking his address.
Well. let's see.
This is the house across the street.
Now. if I were
a house number. I'd be
right about here.
I crop it so all we got
is the reflection.
Reverse and resize.
Tweak the contrast. find some edges.
"3-2-9-4."
So he's across the street
from 3294. but what street?
Well. 1880-ish architecture.
square bay front.
Let's assume the D.C. area.
Check out the lamppost.
Yeah. It places us in one of the two
where they still use those
cast iron modified bishop's crook
street lamps.
For an artist.
you're a good detective.
I think you just insulted me.
Now. I do a search for 3294
in those two zip codes.
and I come up with...
Mad skills. babe.
The landlord said that Cal Warren
worked crazy hours.
you know. he kept to himself.
Every time the landlord asked him.
what he did for a living.
- he always dodged the question.
- Maybe he liked his privacy.
What? So much that he
pays his rent in cash?
I don't know. Bones.
something is weird. It's not right.
There's no letters.
no photographs. not even a bill.
So did you persuade Cam to fire Max?
You think my dad should be
allowed to work at the Jeffersonian?
What. you know. she's just.
trying to do you a favor.
- Well. I didn't ask for a favor.
- Sometimes you don't need to ask.
Got a passport.
This guy's been to countries
I haven't even heard of.
What is this?
I don't know.
It's something you're familiar with?
Foreign currency. lots of it.
Booth found this in tall.
dark and handsome's drawer.
It's an RF proximity card.
And that would be...?
Basically. it's a
super fancy key card.
You wave the card in front of the reader
it logs your infoand the door opens.
Any way to figure out
what door it opens?
Well. if the info on the card
isn't too heavily encrypted.
I heard you tried to get Hodgins
interested in doing an experiment.
Let's just say I planted the seed.
- What? CIA? NSA?
- No.
Dupont Circle.
Special Agent Booth. FBI.
Welcome to the Woodbury School.
How are you?
What's with all the security?
It's precautionary. Our student body
includes chdren of diplomats.
heads of state. CEOs.
- How old is your child?
- Parker? He's seven.
- Has he been evaluated?
- He does just fine.
Most applicant families engage
an educational consultant.
It's not a requirement.
of course. but...
Mr. Donnegan. I think you got this
l wrong.
I know it seems crazy.
but given the demand.
we can only accept the
most qualified applicants.
Parker's a great kid.
The problem is keeping him
that way. isn't it?
68% of our students matriculate
to Ivy League universities.
And it's not because of
our electron microscope or AP classes.
It's because of our Honor Code.
Any violation results
in immediate dismissal.
Why don't I get you
an admissions packet?
Actually. I'm...
I'm here because of
a murder investigation.
- I'm sorry?
- One of your parking access cards
was found in the apartment
of a victim. Cal Warren.
He's not a parent or an employee.
I would know the name.
- Maybe we can check your computer.
- Of course.
No one is issued a key card
without security clearance.
Thanks.
One of our fathers actually implemented
the security system.
He's deputy director of the CIA.
Really?
There he is. Calvin Warren.
Did he happen to work for the CIA?
No. actually.
he works for the president.
Of the United States?
Parents Association.
As a nanny.
A nanny?
28 grand a year.
I didn't pay that much
for 4 years of college.
If you think it's so ridiculous.
why did you save the application?
I didn't save it. I just didn't have
a chance to throw it out yet.
You don't have to be embarrassed.
It's perfectly normal
to want the best for Parker.
Public school was good enough for me.
it's good enough for my kid.
Of course it is. Probably.
What's that supposed to mean?
Parker is a bright.
engaged little boy.
I'm sure he'll do fine
in a large classroom.
- I did.
- Except...
- Except what?
- Your dad was a science teacher.
You're a scientist.
Yes. my education was
enriched at home.
That's what I got to do.
Enrich Parker at home.
In what academics
are you qualified to offer enrichment?
Well...
Ethe could you grab my bag. please?
I am on my way to the
Children First board meeting.
Thank you.
Wexler has the groomer at three.
- Excuse me. Elisbeth King?
- Yes?
We're the FBI.
Do you know a Mr. Calvin Warren?
He was my nanny.
- What happened?
- That's what we're investigating.
Cal dropped off the face
of the earth on Sunday.
He was an excellent nanny.
Well. how is it that
an ex-Special Ops guy
becomes a nanny?
My husband. Richard.
handles defense contracts.
The Middle East. South America.
There were kidnap threats
a couple years ago. he was concerned.
He offered Cal $2.500 a week.
That's very good pay for
a babysitter.
Cal was more like a bodyguard.
That's what got him killed?
Someone after my children?
Could we speak to your children?
Of course.
Okay. so what time on Sunday
did you last see Cal?
- Why?
- Because it's pertinent
to our investigation.
- Wei shen me ta wen zhe ge wen ti?
- Bu zhi dao.
- What?
- Mandarin Chinese.
My father says the Chinese will
run the planet in ten years.
He figures it'll be useful.
- That's very smart.
- Okay. well. here. today.
okay. I run the world.
Bun tyen-shung duh ee-dway ro.
He just called you a stupid.
inbred stack of meat.
Really?
I'm sorry. do you ha
something to say to me?
Dui bu qi. Xie xie.
He. he apologized.
Good. So. you want to tell me
what happened on Sunday?
Well. Cal dropped me off at
the algebra tutor around 8:00.
then took Lexie
to check out a new horse.
In the afternoon. you had
a game against All Saints.
Lacrosse. I got this.
Let's see.
And Cal took you
to the emergency room?
No. He knew one of the moms
was a doctor. so
he figured she'd do a better job.
Looks like the work
of a plastic surgeon.
No. dermatologist.
Dr. Ezralow.
Very competent.
The Royce boy was stitched up
by the same doctor
who said she didn't know Cal Warren.
I'm having her
brought in for questioning.
You think those kids
are better off than Parker?
Of course they are.
They have every advantage:
a wonderful school.
a successful father. mother
committed to charity work.
I spend more time with my houseplants
than they do with their kids.
Children of privilege have
always been raised by staff.
It's how the upper one percent
stays the upper one percent.
Assuming quality education
and adequate supervision.
parents are actually rather
irrelevant beyond a certain age.
- You're kidding me.
- Look at this.
They start Latin in third grade.
That's fantastic.
No. You know what's more important
than academic enrichment?
A loving environment.
You ask anyone.
Parker is a wonderful child. Booth.
You shouldn't feel inadequate.
I'm perfectly
capable of raising my own kid.
- You're being defensive.
- I am not.
It's because
you only have one child.
When you procreate in multiples.
there's less pressure.
Thank you. I feel much better.
This way.
Have a seat.
I apologize. Agent Booth.
When you called and asked
if I knew a Calvin Warren.
I just didn't put it together
with the King's nanny.
- So you did know him?
- Yes. But just as Cal.
My son is on the same
lacrosse team as the King boy.
Did you have
any more dealings with him?
I'm afraid not.
Actually. no. that's not true.
I'm sorry. again.
Calvin came along with us one time
when I took the.
King children up for a ride.
- A ride?
- I'm a pilot.
I own a Senecaive.
Cal got sick. and. well.
the boys thought that was hilarious.
You wouldn't happen
to know how Cal Warren
got a prescription
for painkillers from you?
Isn't that obvious?
That's why he brought Royce King
to me to be stitched up.
To steal my prescription pad.
I have no further questions.
so. thanks for coming in.
I feel stupid for not being able
to put the face with the name.
- I'm so sorry for wasting your time.
- No worries. Have a nice day.
So you know that thing where you insist
that all information goes through you?
Yes. and I'm afraid I'm
immovable on the subject.
And you send out little e-mails
summarizing the case so far?
Yes. plus I check those e-mails
to see if they've been opened.
- That's a very good system.
- Thank you.
Because if you weren't checking.
I probably never would have read
the e-mail that said Booth
questioned a flying dermatologist.
I hope you're not trying
to get some free lotion.
I ran the accelerant sample
through the GC mass spec.
There were traces
of tetra-ethyl lead.
- Have we changed the subject?
- No.
if you hadn't been
so anal about the e-mails.
I never would've known that I discovered
something that wasn't merely interesting
but vital to the investigation.
Which is tetra ethyl lead?
Tetra-ethyl lead was a common
antiknock additive in gasoline
that went out with catalytic
converters and unleaded gas.
Does the flying dermatologist
drive a vintage car?
Maybe. But for sure. the flying
dermatologist flies a plane.
Aviation gas?
The victim's remains were
incinerated by aviation gas.
I'll let Booth know.
Hopefully. she hasn't flown the coop
while you were getting to the point.
I was just trying to be nice.
- You lied to me.
- Yes.
I wrote Cal a prescription
for painkillers.
I shouldn't have.
- That's the truth.
- Yeah. but not this time. Doc.
Now that I know that
you're a world-class liar.
I came just a little bit
more prepared this time.
Take a look at that there.
My flight logs...
- for the past year.
- Yeah.
Oh. looky here. this one here.
Right here.
Yes. I took Cal flying a few times.
Without the kids?
This one here is my favorite.
This particular flight to New York.
You were gone the whole weekend.
All right.
All right. I'll tell you
what you want to know.
No. my husband didn't know I was
having an affair with the Kings'manny.
Would I have killed Cal to
prevent him from finding out?
No. I would not.
Why?
Because my husband doesn't
give a damn who I boff.
Do I know anyone else
who might wish Cal ill?
Yes.
Richard King.
Don't stop. this is great.
Keep going.
Cal told me to sell a stock.
He said he had some insider knowledge
that. this company was in trouble.
I took the tip. made a killing.
That's when I flew him to
New York to say thank you.
And he said "you're
welcome" all weekend.
What's this have to
do with Richard King?
It was Richard King's company.
- How's that look. Max?
- Good. looks good.
Never thought I'd be
doing another experiment.
Dad. what are you doing in here?
Max had a great idea
for an experiment.
Dad. you said you
wouldn't touch evidence.
He's been very careful not to
touch the evidence.
You know. your old man. he reminded
me why I got into science.
- To catch murderers?
- No.
To figure stuff out in amusing ways.
The bones were incinerated
by aviation fuel.
They just need to know. uh. how
strong the wind was basic.
So. figure out how big
a wind blew the bones...
Check the weather charts.
Basic. that's very basic.
But this is the same wind tunnel you
helped me build for the science fair.
Right. a basic wind tunnel. honey.
You won first prize.
I made casts that weigh the same
as the bones we found in that tree.
All right. now...
we put the skull cast
into the wind tunnel
since that
was the largest artifact on the tree.
I didn't touch anything.
The bone begins to move at wind
speeds of 42 miles per hour.
Not enough net force to
achieve aerodynamic lift.
But crank it to 69...
I checked the National Weather Service.
There were windstorms
in that area last week.
A strong nor'easter hit 71
miles per hour late last Tuesday.
That gives us a 48-hour window
for Calvin Warren's murder.
We still don't know where he was
killed or where the body was dumped.
- Wait a minute. I can figure that out.
- Dad. you're fired.
What?
The National Oceanic and
Atmospheric Administration.
The NOAA tracks surface conditions.
We can calculate where the bones started
out if we can plot approximate mass
and reverse the path
of that nor'easterly.
The heavier remains will still
be near the original dump site.
- You see. I'm helping.
- Oh. most definitely is helping.
I'm sorry. Dad. but you're fired.
You took part
in a forensic experiment.
You said you wouldn't. but
you did. so now you're fired.
He didn't touch any of the evidence.
It's okay. kid.
Never mind.
Nice assist. Mick.
Now take him out quick.
No. Mick!
Pass it! Pass it!
Hi. Alexa. How are you?
Shouldn't you be like. studying algebra.
Chinese or solving the world's problems?
I'm cheering for Royce.
He's the goalie.
I watch football.
It's a better sport. It's American.
Lacrosse was invented
by the American Indian.
You can't get much
more American than that.
- Oh. God. what now?
- I'm thinking about
this whole insider trading thing.
I told you everything.
I'm thinking Cal
gives you a tip on a stock.
you sell it.
you make $2 million.$3 million.
it raises questions in my mind.
How did Richard King find out
that Cal spilled insider knowledge?
That's right. Bones.
I don't know.
Well. where were you between
last Sunday and Tuesday night?
- Who is she?
- Don't get jealous. Doc.
Just answer the question.
I was in San Antonio
doing skin grafts on a firefighter
with third-degree burns.
- You've got your own plane.
- You had time to fly back.
You really want me to believe
that Richard King killed Cal.
Cal Warren's remains were
incinerated with aviation gas.
I didn't kill Cal.
You know what. she lies a lot.
I don't think she can help it at all.
- Here's my lawyer's card.
- She's decided not to cooperate.
No. I've decided to watch
my son play lacrosse.
Here's the surface
weather for Tuesday night
when that nor'easter blew
the bones into that tree.
Now. that red X. that's the tree.
The bones must have
traveled along this vector.
Now. given the duration of the
gust and the terrain obstacles.
lift off must have happened
somewhere between
here... and here.
That's on the edge of Queen
Anne's and Kent County.
Good job. excellent experiment.
Don't thank me.
Thank Max Brennan.
How's it going there. Max?
That's the last day with
my kids this afternoon.
I'm toast.
Cam fired you?
No. no. Tempe fired me.
And don't tell me she hasn't got the
authority. because. believe me.
I feel fired.
Sorry. Max.
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
You. are you...
- Are you sleeping with my daughter?
- No.
Why? Are you gay?
- Is she not attractive enough?
- Bones is beautiful.
- Is it because of me?
Because I killed one man. and
we both know he deserved it.
Right. just cut it out. Max.
I'll talk to her.
Probably ain't gonna get
anywhere with her. but...
- I'll talk to her.
- You're a good man.
And I want that for her.
And now I got to go blow
up some soda for some kids.
Okay. according to the calculations.
the bones must have started out
from somewhere in this vicinity.
You know something. Bones?
It's tough being a father.
Parker will be fine.
Peer groups
and random environmental factors
are far more important than family.
How's that a good thing?
Over here!
Agent Booth. over here.
This must have been where
the... body was burned.
You think?
Femur. pelvis...
sternum.
Gunshot trauma to the sternal angle.
The buckshot embedded
in the anterior surface
indicates that the murder weapon
was a 12-gauge shotgun.
- I thought Cal was strangled.
- He was.
Strangled. shot and set on fire.
Someone wanted to make
sure he didn't get home.
Hey. Bones.
look at the family crest.
Looks like that someone came from
king's country home.
Mr. King. we'd like to ask you a
few questions about your nanny.
I really don't see how
I can help you. Agent Booth.
My wife deals with the staff.
You own a 12-gauge shotgun?
Yeah. several.
You're welcome to examine them.
Two months ago. Cal gave
an investor insider knowledge
about your company.
- I didn't know that.
- And if you had known?
I suppose I would
have tried to fire him.
Tried?
I don't think that
Elsbeth would have allowed it.
Was she having an affair with him?
Oh. Bones. such a good one.
You two need to learn focus.
- Excuse me?
- Focus. Focus.
Either accuse me
of killing Cal because
he betrayed business secrets
or because he had sex with my wife.
and then once you've
chosen. then contact my lawyers.
I'd go with the business motive.
I'm very happily married.
Okay. that guy is one cool customer.
Cool like a murderer?
No. I don't know. okay?
I just don't see him
losing his temper
or taking on some
Special Forces vet. that's all.
All right. do you think that
dog comes with a saddle?
Follow me. Bones.
will you. for a second?
What's going on?
What are you doing?
Are you going to urinate in the
gas tank as an act of vandalism?
You kidding me. Bones? I would never
do something like that
to this fine Italian automobile.
Beautiful car. It's Italian. Bones.
Just remember that. Italians
make the best automobiles.
Yeah. There it is.
Okay. Bones. give me. one
of your little baggies.
- I didn't bring evidence bags.
- Thanks. Appreciate it.
We're not at a crime scene.
Why would I bring this bags?
You always have
evidence bags on you.
I've...
I've decided
I'm gonna leave the Jeffersonian.
Why?
Because I fired him.
- You can do that?
- Yeah. Believe me. she can do it.
Well. it's all about proximity
to forensic evidence.
Don't take any offense. but
that's a lot of crap.
It's about proximity to me. Right?
Well. in my opinion.
it isn't your father's presence
that's causing you anxiety.
it's the memory of his absence.
I can understand quantum
mechanics. but I can't understand you.
Well. make it easy.
I'm leaving the Jeffersonian.
You are?
- But I'm staying with you.
- What? In my house?
No. no. no.
Why. is that an offer?
No. Would you...
Would you want me to offer?
No. but thanks for the offer.
It wasn't an offer.
It was a question.
He isn't saying he's
literally staying with you.
He's promising never
to abandon you again.
I'm sorry. but if it wasn't for that
evidence thing.
I'd let you keep your job.
That's simply not true.
Hey. it's all right.
We're good.
Nothing I say has any impact.
I should get back to work.
Oh. geez.
Did she leave any money?
- About the fractured hyoid...
- Yes?
I was just remembering
about a tapeworm.
- I going to need more than that.
- There was a tapeworm in the line.
The one that went to the beer keg.
I was working as a
barback a couple years ago.
There's no flow from the tap line.
First assumption: kink in the line. OK?
What else could it be?
There was a tapeworm in the line.
Eight inches long.
- I learned something from that.
- Drink bottled beer?
The tap don't flow. you
assume the line's got a kink.
The guy's hyoid is broken. you assume
he died from getting strangled.
You found a tapeworm?
I mean. metaphorically?
Yeah. but I don't know
if it's a tapeworm.
I need Dr. Brennan.
I am so your most valuable player.
Now. this is the profile of the
accelerant we found on the bones.
Aviation gas.
And this is the profile of the
gas we took off Booth's tie.
Richard King's car runs on avgas?
He could have siphoned it out of his
own car to burn Cal Warren's remains.
And what is this anomaly?
C6H8O7.
Citric acid?
It's my considered belief that Agent
Booth spilled orange juice on his tie.
I look forward to seeing
him explain that to the jury.
Booth. it's Cam.
I think you're going to want
to getyourself a warrant
to arrest Richard King.
Fractures
on the transverse processes of the C2.
both sides. and the spinous process.
And check out the
occipital protuberance.
Oh. yes.
Maybe this will help Booth
keep Richard King in detention.
Cal wasn't strangled postmortem.
He was dragged.
Strangulation is the kink.
dragging is the tapeworm.
The pattern of marks
is evenly spaced as if
it were from a series
of connected prongs.
What would do that?
A choke chain.
Richard King's a big strong guy.
I don't see him dragging a dead
body around on a choke chain.
That's because he didn't.
The angle of the fracture
is 18 degrees.
Assuming a standard four-foot leash.
whoever dragged
the victim is at most five-five.
So. you're sure you don't want
your attorney present. Mrs. King?
- Let's just get this over with.
- Okay. sounds good to me.
Here's. what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking that.
your country home
is less than a mile
from the spot where
Cal's body was burned.
You had access to the
shotgun. the aviation gas...
You know how many people
work for us. Agent Booth?
Every single one of them had access.
Yeah. I don't think any of them really
would have cared if they found out that.
Cal Warren was trying to
destroy your husband's company.
You have a nice life.
I'm sure you got really angry when you
found out that it was all going away.
You don't understand.
It wasn't about the money.
I had to protect my family.
What do you think?
In my professional
opinion. she didn't whack him.
What? Come on. Cal betrayed them.
Come on. Sweets.
For once. you're right.
- Embrace the win. my friend.
- I'm sorry. but it's Kinesics 101.
You pushed all the right buttons.
but instead of her ego defense system
triggering a stress-response state.
she went straight into
a tacit confession.
Right. which means... she did it.
No. it means she didn't do it.
But she wants you to
believe that she did.
Why would she want to do that?
She's covering for someone.
The only honest thing that she said
was that she had to protect her family.
So we're back to square one.
Sort of.
Geez.
Let me ask you something.
I mean. you're a smart guy.
you went to private school. right?
Yeah. With perfect attendance
through sixth grade. might I add.
That's great.
You don't think that
I'm a lousy dad for not
sending my son to private school?
No.
but you'd be a lousy father if
you didn't torture yourself about it.
Thanks.
Hold on. Booth.
I reviewed the placement of
the shotgun pellet wounds.
The trajectory indicates that
whoever shot Cal
was significantly
shorter than Mrs. King.
- I don't think she did it.
- Right. thanks.
You see. we got a court order
for your cell phone and your laptop.
You know nothing you text
or IM is really private.
I knew that.
Really? Because. you know.
we checked your text messages. and.
we found one from a couple
weeks ago that's a little weird.
This one is from the
night that Cal was killed.
"Bring it over now.
Parents both gone."
- Stop this. Richard.
- No. I want to hear it.
It turns out that Alexa. here.
had a project due on Ancient Greece.
You spent three days
complaining about it.
- Why didn't you just do it?
- I didn't want to.
- It was stupid.
- Stupid?
- How about this one?
- "D manny will do it.
He can't say no. He works for me."
But Cal really did say no.
didn't he?
Because you paid a hundred bucks
to somebody else to do it for you.
Someone by the name
of Dakota Shearcroft.
Oh. my God.
Yeah. I think it's a stupid name. too.
So what happened?
Did Cal catch you?
He threatened to tell the school.
- Why wouldn't he have just told us?
- Cal said you wouldn't do anything.
You never do.
- He said I had to learn a lesson.
- What kind of lesson?
They would have kicked me
out of school! Zero tolerance.
My friends are at that school.
I got the gun out of the garage
and I shot him.
Mom came home and saw.
I drove the body to the country
house.
took it into the woods
and burned it.
She's my daughter.
I had to protect her.
No. you did what you always do.
Make everything bad go away.
It's counterproductive to raise children
in a world without consequences.
It looks like little Alexa here
is going to have to come face-to-face
with some pretty nasty consequences.
But not the kind of consequences
you're going to have to face. Mrs. King.
Okay. Parker. this is called
the candy mint-soda experiment.
You can do this
for your dad at home.
So. Mom copped to
conspiracy to avoid a trial.
- She'll spend some time in prison.
- How much?
Not enough. My opinion.
she ruined that little girl's life.
What about the little girl?
Removed from the family.
institutionalized for a couple of years.
Then it's back to ponies
and tennis lessons?
Well. Caroline should
charge her as an adult.
She's 11 years old. Bones.
Yeah. she's old
enough to speak Chinese.
They don't take that into account.
Man. when that little girl killed Cal
she killed the best father she had.
Well. sometimes it's hard
to appreciate what you've got.
Look at him. Parker
has never liked science before.
Are you still thinking of
sending him to Woodbury?
I torched the application.
I'm thinking there's something
to be said for middle class.
You sure he's going to be all right?
Sure. Well. probably.
Probably. like.
what do you mean. probably?
What the hell
are they doing anyways?
Disrupting the surface
tension of a two-liter cola.
Right.
Is that the last one?All
right. put it in the tube.
And then we'll both
take a step back.
Don't fire Max.
Let him keep his job.
He's a teacher. he's not a janitor.
I can't overlook the sanctity
of the forensic lab. Booth.
Yeah.
maybe you can overlook it for me.
For you?
Yeah.
Personal favor.
What. like a partner thing?
A partner thing.
I know you. Booth.
You're trying to do me a favor
by telling me it's a favor for you.
No.
No. I...
I can't afford that school.
I can't enrich Parker.
not with the science thing. but...
you can. Max can.
Do it again.
Daddy! Daddy. look what I did!
I blew it up!
Yeah. I saw little man.
Look at my dad!
Look at my boy there with your dad.
Okay.
Yes...
- All right.
- Thanks. Bones.